<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Android engineer blog</title>
    <link>https://maxshashkov.tech/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Android engineer blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 11:50:01 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maxshashkov.tech/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Managing device screen brightness in your android application</title>
      <link>https://maxshashkov.tech/post/screen_brightness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 11:50:01 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maxshashkov.tech/post/screen_brightness/</guid>
      <description>Why might you need to control the brightness of the device screen? For example: You are developing an application that displays QR codes that are read by the scanner. For better readability, we need to maximize image contrast and for that we can change the brightness to the maximum.
Before start to control screen brightness, we must answer for one question: &amp;ldquo;Do we want to control the brightness of the screen only when our app is active, or does it need to record the setting value after our app is shut down?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to establish SSH tunelling between host and remote server</title>
      <link>https://maxshashkov.tech/post/ssh_tunneling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 11:36:01 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maxshashkov.tech/post/ssh_tunneling/</guid>
      <description>Local TCP forwarding Problem: you need to connect from your local machine to postgres db hosted remotely (for example on VPS). But direct remote connections to database are not allowed
Let&amp;rsquo;s assume we have a remote server named &amp;ldquo;host 2&amp;rdquo; with application (PostgreSQL for instance) which accepts incoming connections on port 5432. Instead of connecting to port 5432 remotely (which is insecure and might be blocked by the host&amp;rsquo;s firewall) we can connect to port 32 allowed for remote connections by host&amp;rsquo;s 2 firewall.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
